Guide to the John Poulos and Constantine Poulos Papers TAM.114
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series II: Greek Wartime (WWII) Resistance & Aftermath
  - Subseries II:Q: EAM
    - Monthly Review -, Dec 1972 (Box 7, Folder data_value_missing_8dae2a2fa24a01153146090ec1a49c06)
    - Greece in the 40's, undated (Box 7, Folder data_value_missing_5b40a530921e838b58dc9a06ab24c523)
    - Monthly Review -, Feb 1974 (Box 7, Folder data_value_missing_7e12fefeec8e7631a068678d32e2da80)
    - Monthly Review -, Apr 1978 (Box 7, Folder data_value_missing_6c8809e7aa82a90efd36121e0823ac4a)
    - Monthly Review -, May 1978 (Box 7, Folder data_value_missing_0f05d200132c06405492298a270986eb)
    - Challenge to Freedom, undated (Box 7, Folder data_value_missing_518a77def9a1bea5a1d15bf7b1a2d5ba)
  - Subseries II:R: Recent Correspondence
    - Koraes Letters, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Subseries II:S: Canada
    - Canada, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Bibliography, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
      (Greek/English)
    - White Book, May 1944-Mar 1945 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - National Herald - New York, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Pamphlet, undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Rizos, 1944-1945 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - GAM ELAS Civil War EDA, 1977-1978 (Box 8, Folder 8)
      (Greece to file [written 1977-78])
    - ELAS-Reminiscences. Stalinist, 1947-1948 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - EMA: Why it lost out, undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Zaharides also Aris, undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Greece - KKE-ELAS Civil war, 1977-1978 (Box 8, Folder 12)
      (written 1977-78, not filed)
    - Article: L.S. Stavrianos, undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Index: Newspapers only, undated (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Bibliography of books - Greek, undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - LOSH Index, undated (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - NYU - Tamiment Library, undated (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Greece - Maoists, 1965-1966 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Greece, 1943 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Article, undated (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - NYU Index, undated (Box 8, Folder 22)
      (in the making) - Greece
    - U.S.S.R., undated (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Theodorakis, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Greece - Left parties and organizations, undated (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Brussels, 1972-1973 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - J. Poulos: Modern Greek Studies Association, undated (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Greece - Chronology of Modern Greek History - Initials of various groups, undated (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - LaVerite, Jun 9, 1933 (Box 8, Folder 29)
      (No. 158)
    - Cyprus, undated (Box 8, Folder xx.)
    - Yugoslavia, undated (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Unfiled-political-1, undated (Box 8, Folder 31)
- Series III: Greek Trotskyism and Early Marxism
  - Subseries III:A: Greece - Modern History plus KKE - LOSH Indexes
    - May Day, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Killings in Greece, undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Greece: KKE -, Dec 1944 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Greece: KKE, 1944-1949 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Greece: KKE History - 60 years, undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Greece: Varkiza - A Stalinist Betrayal, undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Greece: 4th Up to Mextaxas to the civil war, undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Archio-Marxists, undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Greece: Modern 4th plus KKE history, undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - J. Poulos' letter: Petsopoulos in the KKE, undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Trotsky murdered, undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - D.E.K. document to Trotskyist Merger Conference, undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Greece: 4th history, undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Greece: 4th International papers, 1944-1946 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Greece 4th - 50 years to the Left Oppostion, undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Greece, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Greece: 4th Yalta, undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Leninist opposition of GCP, undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - KKE Criticism, undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Greece: Mike Stevens' articles, undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Greece 4th in war time, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - 4th EAM,KKE and Trotskyism during occupation, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - 4th Trotskyism and Stalinism in world war II, undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - 4th International, undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Castoriades, circa 1961-1965 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Varkiza 4th, undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Photocopies of various articles on Greek issues, undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Greece 4th Vitsoris-LD Trotsky discussion plus historical notes on left opposition, undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Greece 4th: Vitsoris, undated (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Greece: Trotskyist - December, undated (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Greece: Communist Review cover Vol. 1, No. 1., Jan 1922 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Greece: Communist Review Vol. 2, No. 6., Jun 1922 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - (articles) Unfiled - Greece, undated (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Greece: Archeio-Marxists killed by Stalinists, undated (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Greece: Athanasiades, undated (Box 10, Folder 19)
      (Thalasinoe)
    - Articles in Greek, undated (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - 4th Pouliopoulos, undated (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Greece: 4th Stina, undated (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Greece: Vitte, undated (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Greece: Pictures of Trotskyists*, undated (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Greece: Prison locations, undated (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Loukas - December Days, 1944 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - France: Addresses, undated (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Ilios Yannakakis - The KKE, undated (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - KKE, 1967-1969 (Box 10, Folder 29)
- Series IV: John Poulos Correspondence and 4th International
  - Subseries IV:A: General
    - Lenin's speech on Ultraleftism, undated (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - In closet files, undated (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - C. and J. Poulos, undated (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - L. A. Mike Stevens, undated (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Subseries IV:B: Correspondence
    - Breitman, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Hansen, undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - B.D.I.C. Michel Dreyfus, undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Greeks in C.L.A., undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Greece: Lars Baerentzen, undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Review of KKE Kousoulas' book, undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Richter, undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Louis Sinclair, undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - France: Nikos Syringas, undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Edward Oler, undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
      (Hugo Oehler)
    - Hemlock Quarterly, undated (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Mail Maytag-Ann, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Alan Wald, undated (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Vlanton, undated (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Corr: Stravianos, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Catalogs, undated (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Oberst, undated (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Anastassiadis*, undated (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Thomas Stamm, undated (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Greece corr: Stina, undated (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Greece corr: Helen, undated (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - CLA Internal Bulletin #17, undated (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Spartacists, undated (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - N.Y. Times, undated (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Dalven, undated (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Lynn, undated (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Louis Basky, undated (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - B.J. Field, undated (Box 11, Folder 28)
      (Gould)
    - Glotzer, undated (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - Harvard, undated (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - Greece: Alexandra Topping, undated (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - C.E.R.M.T.R.I. J.C. Orveillen, undated (Box 11, Folder 32)
    - Gankakis, undated (Box 11, Folder 33)
    - Rene Dazy, undated (Box 11, Folder 34)
    - Sklavos, undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Nikos: Material mailed to him, undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Nikos: 2nd mailing, undated (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Lynn CIO - xerox, undated (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Felekis, undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Katpaba Iwavra(Kowa), undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Greece: Myrtos, undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Maurice Spector, undated (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Greece: Spartakos, 19311933 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Greece corr: L. Kastritis, undated (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Athens, undated (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Subseries IV:C: Correspondence - Scotland
    - 4th International, undated (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Greece: Elections, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Daylos Vol. 1, No. 1, 1931 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Daylos Vol. 1, No. 2, 1932 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - 4th Debates with KKE -, 1946 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Greece: Bulletin Interieur Vol. 1, No. 8, Oct 1945 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Greece: Bulletin Interieur Vol. 2, No. 14 Secretariat International, undated (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - France: Bulletin IV -, 1938 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Bulletin of workers, undated (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Greece: CLO Bulletin #2 -, Mar 1, 1931 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Greece: CLO Bulletin, Apr 1931-May 1931 (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Greece: CLO Bulletin, May 1931 (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Greece: CLO Bulletin, May 1931-Jun 1931 (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Greece: CLO #15, Jun 1934 (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - The Communist - CLA -, 1932 (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - Greek Canada, undated (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - New Beginning, undated (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - Marxist Bulletin, undated (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - Magazine of the worker's struggle, undated (Box 12, Folder 30)
    - Pamphlet cover - Greek, undated (Box 12, Folder 31)
    - Greece: Deltio, undated (Box 12, Folder 32)
    - Articles in Greek, undated (Box 12, Folder 33)
    - International Bulletin, undated (Box 12, Folder 34)
    - Greece: 4th, 1967-1969 (Box 12, Folder 35)
    - Greece: 4th, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 36)
    - Greece: 4th, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 37)
    - Greece: 4th, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 38)
    - Greece: Classics-Marxist translations to Greek, undated (Box 12, Folder 39)
  - Subseries IV:D: Journals and Newspapers
    - Newspaper in Greek, undated (Box 12, Folder 40)
    - Newspaper in Greek, undated (Box 12, Folder 41)
- Series V: Junta & Resistance, Other Subject Files
  - Newsletter: Modern Greek Society Vol. V, No. 1; Vol. III, No. 1, undated (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - A Greek Book, undated (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Cartoons:, 1920, 1936-1937, 1940 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Cartoons: 1967-1972 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    (Poster of a Greek soldier, Greece under Democracy and new constitution)
  - Patriotic Front, undated (Box 13, Folder 5)
    (Articles about the Junta arresting and prosecuting members of the Patriotic Front; Bulletin of democratic resistance)
  - Front Line and other radical publications Free Voice of Greece Demokratia, undated (Box 13, Folder 6)
    (are all against Junta and its American sponsors)
  - Hellenic Review-Vol. 1, No. 3-5, undated (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Litton, U.S. Industries, etc., undated (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Pappas - Agnew, undated (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous publications and articles including: Written works issues by Panhellenic Liberation Movement re: Democracy and Constitution Newsletters re: torture in Greece; Articles re: government; Articles re: Greece withdrawing from Council of Europe; Poster: Advertisement of Greeks willingness to fight fascism; Articles: Repression policies employed by government., undated (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Junta Leaders, undated (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Eleutheria - Vol. IV, No. 1-4, undated (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Greek Report -, Mar 1969-May 1970, Dec 1971 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Antistasi, undated (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Articles re: Colonies in Greece; The besieged king; Military takeover, Apr 1967 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Royalty, undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - EDA History, undated (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Articles and newsletter, undated (Box 14, Folder 4)
    (Greek and English) ESAK Bulletin
  - 1965 Econ. Statistics, undated (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Underground, undated (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Report on Greece - Newspapers -- Torture; Resistance; Constitution; Economy, undated (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Foreign Report -- Articles: Appeals to Americans, Apr 1967-Jun 1970 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Free Greece Papers, undated (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - American aid to Junta -, 1968 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - America's Threat, undated (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - C.I.A, undated (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - NATO and the middle east, undated (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Tortures, undated (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Economic, undated (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - National Unity, undated (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Articles: Greek and English -- Re: Vietnam; Constitution in Greece; Rigged Greek referendum, undated (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Publication, undated (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Greek Papers, undated (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Press Committee, undated (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Papandreou, undated (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Greece: J. P. Letters, undated (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Greece not filed, undated (Box 14, Folder 23)
    (Greek and English) -- Women political prisoners; Terror in Greece; Military
  - Nixon -- Junta censors theaters; Greek Travesty; Dialouge with Nixon; Junta's eyes on Nixon, undated (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Democratia, undated (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Paul Nord -- Verses about Greece and Junta, undated (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Greece-not filed -- A Greek newsletter; Articles: Life in military Greece; Letters by political prisoners of Greece*, 1967-1970 (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Greece Committee, undated (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Onassis, undated (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - Georgakas, Dan: Guide to Anit-Junta Material Prepared for Oral History of the American Left Project, undated (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Georgakas, Dan: Anti-Junta Correspondence, 1968-1972 (Box 15, Folder 1A)
  - Anti-Junta Articles and Personalities, c. 1967-c. 1974 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Anti-Juna Artists, c. 1967-c. 1974 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - The Front Line [newsletter], 1972-1973 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - "Greek Accent": Green American / Greek Language Activities, etc., c. 1967-c. 1974 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Historical Background, undated (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Ritsos - Z [motion picture] - Theodorakas and Demokratia, c. 1967-c. 1974 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - George Polk Awards: Biographical/Historical Material, Media Coverage, Program, 1998 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - George Polk Awards: Photographs (Including a picture of Rea Polk [widow]), 1998 (Box 15, Folder 9)
- Series VI: Greek Language Monographs & Serials
  (4 linear feet)
  - Monographs, undated (Box 16, Folder data_value_missing_b923ac7363f7a0da1f541625fd4ee71f)
  - Serials, undated (Box 17, Box 18, Box 19)
- Series VII: Scrapbook on Greek Civil War
  - Scrapbook, 1940-1948 (Box 20)
- Series VIII: Addendum
  - Clippings by and about the Poulos Brothers and things Greek, 1969-1987 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Labor Action: Clippings, 1940s (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Letter in Greek, undated (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Obituaries, 1981, 1986 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Poulos, John: CIO; Lynn Massachusetts, undated (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Poulos, John: FOIA Files (With 1998 Cover Letter), undated (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Department of Justice Report: Propaganda in the Greek American Community, Apr 21, 1944 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Article: "Who Killed George Polk" in More Magazine, May 1977 (Box 21, Folder 8)
- Series IX: Photographs
  This series contains copy prints of photographs of Constantine and John Poulos, and a photograph (shot for Life by photographer Dimitri Kessel) of (Greek) National Liberation Front ("EAM-ELAS") leader Giorges Siantos "addressing rally on the occasion of the liberation of Athens" (apparently from a balcony), with Constantine Poulos standing next to him. It also contains photographs of Greek-American performers Nitsa Tsaganea and George Vitsioris.
  - Assorted Photographs, undated (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Photographs by Dimtri Kessel, Dec 1944 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Constantine Poulos, 1946, undated (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - John Poulos, 1956, 1969 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Tsaganea, Nitsa (Vitsioph), undated (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Vitsoris, George, undated (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Photographs, cartoons, 1931-1967 (Box 23)